Finding Aid for the Faculty Women's Club. Scrapbooks and photographs. 1942-2004.
UCLA Library Special Collections
Faculty Women's Club. Scrapbooks and photographs.
1942-2004
University Archives Record Series 696
UCLA Library Special Collections
1.2 linear ft. (3 boxes)
Record Series 696 contains scrapbooks and photographs from the Faculty Women's club, dating from 1948 to 2004.
Faculty Women's Club. 1918-
Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Historical Note
The Faculty Women's Club (FWC) originated as a political action group at Los Angeles Normal School, focused on gathering support for the creation of a four-year college in Southern California. When the Los Angeles State Normal School became the Southern Branch of the University of California in 1919, the group's initial political objective was met.
Subsequently, the FWC met to consider the club's future. By the spring of 1920 the first constitution and purpose of the FWC of the Southern Branch of the University of California had been drafted. The Club's purpose became the promotion of good fellowship for UCLA women faculty, faculty wives, women staff, and wives of staff who are directly connected with the academic aspects of the University. FWC also sought to promote educational and social activities and to provide educational scholarships for UCLA students.
Scope and Content
Record Series 696 contains scrapbooks and photographs from the Faculty Women's club, dating from 1948 to 2004.
This is an active record series; additional University records are expected to be added.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 4475136
- Scrapbook (original)., 1942-1956. (Box 42, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook (archival copy)., 1944-1947. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  Scope and Content
  The subject of this scrapbook is the Clubhouse.
- Scrapbook (original)., 1944-1947. (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook (archival copy)., 1946-1950. (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Scrapbook (archival copy)., 1950-1956. (Box 42, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook (original)., 1956-1958. (Box 42, Folder 6)
- Scrapbook (original)., 1958-1959. (Box 42, Folder 7)
- Scrapbook (archival copy with some original photographs)., 1956-1960. (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook (original)., 1959-1960. (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook (original)., 1984-1985. (Box 43, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook (original with photocopied articles)., 1985-1991. (Box 43, Folder 4)
- Scrapbook (original)., 1986. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  The subject of this scrapbook is the Conference of Southland Campus Women's Clubs.
- Scrapbook (original with photocopied articles)., 1985-1993. (Box 44, Folder 1)
- 75th Anniversary Scrapbook (original, archival) Hooper-Chapman, Bernice., 1945-1946. (Box 44, Folder 2)
- 75th Anniversary Images., 1992-1993. (Box 44, Folder 3)
- 75th Anniversary Scrapbook (original, archival) Asimow and Winstein. (Box 44, Folder 4)
- 75th Anniversary Scrapbook (original, archival) "Selections from the plays of W. Somerset Maugham.", ca. 1961-1968. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  May 16, 1961: the program for the general meeting was "Selections from the plays of W. Somerset Maughan." This photograph, taken by Thelner Hoover, is of the cast for the performance. Back Row: Professor Melnitz. Middle Row: Dorothy Robbins, flanked by two male graduate students. Front Row: Fannie Grant, Dorothy Foulger, Sylvia Winstein, Judy Murphy, Carmela Speroni and Lorelei Libby.
- Spring luncheon; tennis party., 2004. (Box 44)
  Scope and Contents note
  photographic prints.